Guide to the Erica Jong papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Erica Jong Papers,
1955-2011
[Bulk Dates: 1965-2004].
Jong, Erica.
94 linear ft. (102 boxes: 84 record storage cartons 16 document boxes, 2 oversize boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY. 10027
MS#1438
6217591
Erica Jong (b. 1942) is an American writer and teacher whose works are often associated with sexuality and feminism. The Erica Jong Papers consist of drafts of Jong's works of poetry, fiction, and non-fiction. The collection also includes project and research files, correspondence, personal memorabilia, photographs, audio-visual materials and printed matter.
Biographical Note
Author Erica Mann Jong was born on March 26th, 1942, in New York City and was raised on Manhattan's Upper-Westside. Her father, Seymour Mann, founded Seymour Mann Imports, a giftware and home accents store; her mother, Eda Mirsky Mann, a painter, designed many of the dolls in the Connoisseur Doll Collection sold through her husband's business. Jong, a middle child, has two sisters Susanna Mann Daou and Claudia Mann Oberweger. Jong attended the High School of Music and Art, then located on the campus of City University in Hamilton Heights, from which she graduated in 1959. The family, by all accounts, led a comfortable life.
While taking her degree at Barnard College (BA 1963) and her Masters in 18th Century English Literature at Columbia University (1965), Jong published two volumes of poetry--Fruits & Vegetables and Half-Lives. Jong entered the international literary scene with her best-selling first novel, Fear of Flying (1973), a semi-autobiographical first-person narrative depicting a woman's search for identity and fulfillment. The book, an immediate sensation, has since sold over 18 million copies and has been translated into multiple languages. The novel's protagonist, Isadora Wing, went on to star in many of Jong's subsequent novels, including How to Save Your Own Life, Parachutes & Kisses, and Any Woman's Blues. Thus far, as her official websites states, Jong has published "20 books, including eight novels, six volumes of poetry, six books of non-fiction and numerous articles" in major magazines and newspapers. Also known for her association with American writer Henry Miller, Jong wrote The Devil at Large (1993) in honor of their friendship and shared literary aesthetic.
Jong is a teacher as well as a writer and has taught courses or conducted workshops at City University of New York, the Overseas Division of the University of Maryland in Germany, Barnard College, Bennington College, Breadloaf Writers Conference, Ben Gurion University in Israel and the Salzburg Seminar in Vienna. Among her awards are the United Nations Award for Excellence in Literature, Poetry Magazine's Bess Hokin Award and France's Deauville Award for Literary Excellence.
In 1996 Jong endowed the Erica Mann Jong '63 Writing Fellows Fund at Barnard College.
Jong has been married four times: her first, and briefest marriage, was to Michael Werthman, whom she married while she was still an undergraduate; Jong and psychiatrist Allan Jong were married in 1966; in 1977 she married author Jonathan Fast with whom she had her one, and only child, also an author, Molly Miranda Fast-Jong; in 1989 Jong married attorney Kenneth David Burrows, a graduate of Brown University and Fordham University Law School, to whom she is still married.
Scope and Content
This collection contains the correspondence, writings, files, personal materials, printed and audio/visual material relating to Erica Jong's writing and personal life. Correspondence ranges from 1958 to 2004, and comprises a wide variety of correspondents, including business and literary contacts, friends, fans, and relatives.
Among the writings are notes, drafts, correspondence, and publication material pertaining to all of Jong's major published novels and essay and poetry collections, including Fear of Flying, and drafts of several unpublished novels and the scripts for a number of unproduced television series and films. In addition, there is a large quantity of material relating to Jong's book on Henry Miller, The Devil at Large--such material includes correspondence and audio and written interviews. Within the "Personal" series are Jong's early diaries and daybooks, as well as material from Barnard and during her time living in Germany.
The series of "Erica Jong Files", organized by Jong, include research, publication, project, and personal files, which contain primarily legal and business correspondence pertaining to Jong's work, finances, and various business projects.
Among the printed materials are books and journals collected by Jong, as well as newspaper and magazine clippings about Jong. Finally, the Audio/Visual material includes recordings of a number of Jong's readings and appearances on television and radio.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in six series:
Series I: Correspondence, 1958-2004
Series II: Writings, 1937-2011
Sub-series II.1: Poetry, 1966-1998
Sub-series II.2: Fiction, 1973-2011
Sub-series II.3: Non-fiction, 1937-1999
Sub-series II.4: Scripts and Screenplays
Sub-series II.5: Writings by Others
Series III: Personal, 1955-1990
Series IV: Erica Jong Files--as organized by Jong, 1970-2008
Sub-series IV.1: Personal / Business Files, 1974-2008
Sub-series IV.2: Project Files, 1970-1993
Sub-series IV.3: Business Files, 1974-1995
Sub-series IV.4: Publication Files, 1970-1993
Series V: Printed Material, 1963-2011
Series VI: Audio/Visual Materials, 1962-2000
Subjects
Barnard College.; Fast, Jonathan.; Jong, Erica.; Jong-Fast, Molly, 1978-; Miller, Henry, 1891-1980.; Authors, American--20th century.; Erotica.; Erotica and women.; Eroticism in literature.; Feminism and literature.; Sexuality and literature.; Diaries.; Correspondence.
Access Restrictions
This collection has restrictions related to student grades, legal and financial documents. The following material is restricted: Box 2, folder 16; Box 62, folders 12-21; Box 63, folders2; Box 70, folders 11 and 12; Box 71; Box 72, folders 1-14; Box 73, folders, 1, 14-16; Box 74, folders 1-13; Box 87, folder 30; Box 88; Box 89; Box 90, folders 1-8.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
Erica Jong Purchase 2007
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1958-2004
  This series is arranged chronologically and alphabetically. The chronological correspondence includes both personal and business correspondence and is organized by decade from the early 1970s through 2011. The alphabetically arranged material retains Jong’s original ordering by person, and includes brief correspondence with a number of figures from the literary, political, and film industries. The folder titles in this section reproduce Jong’s own titles. A cache of letters from Jong’s time as a student at Barnard and Columbia, correspondence from her time living in Germany with her then husband, Allan Jong, and fan mail are also in this series.
  - Chronological, 1973-2004
    - 1970s (4 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 1 to 4)
    - 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1980s (16 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 6 to 21)
    - 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 1990s (2 of 17 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 23 to 24)
    - 1990s (15 of 17 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 1 to 15)
    - 1990s--Author's Guild (Box 2, Folder 16)
      [Restricted until 2040]
    - 2000s (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Alphabetical, 1970-1987
    - General, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Alther, Lisa, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Amichai, Yehunda, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Atwood, Margaret, 1972-1985 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Avedon, Burt, 1977-1978, Undated (with Transcript of Tapes) (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Axinn, Donald, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Bach, Alice, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Barber, Ben, 1975-1987 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Barty-King, Mark, 1978, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Bates, Jon, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Bergman, Ingmar, 1976-1982 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Berheim, Kurt, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Berek, John, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Bernard, Bina, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Birenbaum, Caroline, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Birstein, Ann, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Bold, Alan, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bookbinder, 1979-1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Brogger, Suzanne, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Broner, Esther, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Brown, Arvin, 1982-1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Brown, Helen Gurley, 1977-1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Brown, Rosellen, 1970, 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Broyard, Anatole, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Burgess, Anthony, 1979-1986 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Chabrier, Hortense, 1982-1985 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Charney, Maurice, 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Cheever, John, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Chesler, Phyllis, 1976-1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Chester, Laura, 1977-1987 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Clifford, James, 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Collins, Connie, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Collins, Judy, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Connery, Sean, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Cooper-Clark, Diana, 1980-1986 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Cox, Virginia, 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Darling, Grace, 1975-1984 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Davis, Hope, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Delbanco, Nick, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Diehl, Digby, 1976-1985 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Dillon, Martin, 1974-1981 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Dychtwald, Ken, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Edwards, Page, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - English, Diane, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Evans, Joni, 1979-1985 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Fast, Howard and Bette, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Field, Edward, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Follett, Ken, 1980-1986 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Fonda, Jane, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Francke, Linda Bird, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Frankfort, Ellen, 1977-1983 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Franks, Michael, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - French, Marilyn, 1979-1984 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Friday, Nancy, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Frym, Gloria, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Fujita, S. Neil, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Gilbert, Sandra and Susan Gubar, 1979-1986 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Goedicke, Patricia, 1971-1982 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Goulianos, Joan, 1978-1983 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Granger, Janet, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Gray, Francine, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Green, Gerald, Undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Green, Hannah, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Greer, Germaine, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Guenther, John, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Hadas, Pamela, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Hamilton, Gene, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Hayes, Muriel, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Heilbrun, Carolyn, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Hellman, Lillian, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Höhs, Liselotte, 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Holm, Astrid, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Houston, Bob, 1982-1985 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Irving, Shyla, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Janeway, Elizabeth, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Karetsky, Gerri, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Kaufman, Bel, 1979-1986 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - King, Stephen, 1979-1984 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Klein, Marcus, 1975 (With Letters from Leslie Fiedler) (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Klein, Norma, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Knop, Pat, Undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Kronhausen, Eberhard, 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Kutzin, Alice, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Lauder, Leonard and Evelyn, 1980-1987 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Levin, Ira, 1978, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Leven, Jeremy (Martin Levin),1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Licht, Judy, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Liebert, Robert, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Lifshin, Lyn, 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lord, Betty, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Love, Iris, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - MacShane, Frank, 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Mann, Seymour and Eda, 1980-1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Mason, Barbara, 1978-1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Mee, Charles, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Michi (Kyoko Michishita), 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Miller, Arthur and Inge Morath, 1983-1987 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Minck, Eric, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Mitchell, Stephen, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Moers, Ellen, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Nitzsche, Jane Chance, 1978-1983, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 13 to 14)
    - Nicolai, Adeodato, 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - O'Brien, Edna, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Occhiuzzi, Franco, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Onassis, Jackie, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Ozick, Cynthia, 1972-1987 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Packard, William, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Peer, Liz, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Phillips, Robert, 1971-1987 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Plumb, J.H., 1979-1983 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Previn, Dory, 1975, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Reardon, Joan, 1978-1984 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Rich, Adrienne, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Robinson, Jill, 1983-1987 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Rostas, Susan, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Rothberg, Arlyne, 1980-1984 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Rukeyser, Muriel, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Ryan, Michael, Undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Sarton, May, 1976, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Schiff, Gunther, 1973-1980 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Schoijet, M, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Schulman, Grace, 1979-1983 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Shulman, Alix Kates, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Showalter, Elaine, 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Simon, Carly, 1982, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Simpson, Louis, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Skylar, Dusty, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Smith, Carol, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Sopher, Sharon, 1979-1981 (With Poetry and Script) (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Spector, Sally, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Spiegelman, Joel, 1980-1987 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Steinberg, David and Blue, 1978-1985 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Sternburg, Janet, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Stone, Merlin, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Targ, William, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Thomas, Dom M., 1983-1987 (with Transatlantic Journal) (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Thorvall, Kerstin, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Thwaite, Anthony, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Ticknor & Fields, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Toth, Emily, 1977-1984
      - Correspondence, 1977-1984 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - Inside Peyton Place--Uncorrected Proof, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 54)
      - Women of Wit--Viking Press, Undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Ullman, Liv, 1976, 1979, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Untermeyer, Louis, 1971-1978, (3 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 1 to 3)
    - U.S. Senators, etc., 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Updike, John, 1973-1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Vogel, Vivica, 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Wahl, Nicholas, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Wax, Judith, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Weise, Liaria, 1976-1987 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Weldon, Fay, 1981-1987 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Wheat, Chip, 1976-1982 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Wiinblad, Bjorn, 1977-1985 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Winters, Nancy, 1978-1985 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Wolfe, Linda, 1977-1983 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Zacharia, Don, 1981-1985 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - "Author's Guild Letters," 1991, (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 16 to 17)
  - "Answered", 1975 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Acropole Press, 1979-1987 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Capra Press, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - "Crazy Letters," 1980-1983 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Early Letters, 1957-1975 (3 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 22 to 24)
  - "Famous People," 1976-1987 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Fan Mail, 1970s-1999
    - General, 1970s-1985 (18 of 24 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 2 to 19)
    - General, 1974-1999 (6 of 24 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 1 to 6)
    - Audio Tape, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Friends, 1969-1971 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "General Corresp," 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Hubbard Communications Office, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Invitations and Requests, 1984-1986 (2 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 11 to 12)
  - LA Times Book Review, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - "Letters to Editor," 1972 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - "Literary Agent", 1985 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - "Literacy Volunteers of America", 1992 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - "Miscellaneous Correspondence," 1976-1987 (3 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 17 to 19)
  - "Miscellaneous Personal," 1976-1981, (2 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 20 to 21)
  - The Perfect Man, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Personal, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - "Personal From EJ," 1980-1987, (3 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 1 to 3)
  - "Personal To EJ," 1977-1987, (3 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 4 to 6)
  - Poetry, 1962-1976
    - General, 1962-1968 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Anthologies and Prizes, 1970-1976 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Submission Letters, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Presses and Magazines, 1969-1972 (2 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 10 to 11)
  - "Professional-Notes of Thanks, Etc, Papers," 1992-1994, (3 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 12 to 14)
  - Teaching Positions, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Templin, Charlotte--Interview, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - "Weird and Funny," 1976-1981, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 1 to 2)
- Series II: Writings, 1937-2011
  Encompassing Jong's entire writing career, this series consists of typescripts, computer printouts, notepads, and proofs and includes drafts of poetry, novels, non-fiction monographs, essays, articles, screenplays, plays, and related peripheral materials such as promotional documents and audio tapes. As a whole, this series reflects the evolution and consistencies of her writing practice--first drafts often written longhand on yellow legal-sized notepads, and subsequent typed or computer drafts.
  - Subseries II. 1: Poetry, 1966-1998
    This subseries contains notes, drafts, proofs, correspondence, and publicity material related to all of Jong's published books of poetry, including At the Edge of the Body, Becoming Light, Fruits & Vegetables, Half-Lives, Loveroot, and Ordinary Miracles. Also included are drafts of a number of unpublished poems, particularly located in the “A to Z” folder, as well as several notebooks containing handwritten notes and early drafts.
    - General, 1972-1976 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - A to Z, 1976-1978 (3 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 4 to 6)
    - At the Edge of the Body, 1976-1979
      - General, 1977 (3 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 7 to 9)
      - Cover Proofs, Undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Drafts, 1978-1979
        - General, Undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
        - Editor’s Proofs, Undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
        - Master Galleys, 1979 (2 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 13 to 14)
        - "Original Poetry Ms.", 1978 (Box 9, Folder 15)
        - Uncorrected Proofs, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 16)
        - Xerox Galleys, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - "Fourth Collection of Poems", Undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - "Poems in Progress," 1976 (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - "Work Sheets", Undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - "X-tras", Undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - "Baby Poems", 1980 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Becoming Light, 1987-1991
      - Drafts, 1987-1991
        - General, Undated (3 of 6 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 23 to 25)
        - General, Undated (3 of 6 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 1 to 3)
        - Edited Manuscript, Undated (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 4 to 5)
        - Galleys, 1991 (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 6 to 7)
        - Manuscript, circa. 1987 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - 'New York Is Book Country' Talk, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Sample Pages, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Children’s Poetry, Undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - "Christmas Poems," 1971 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - "The Collaborators," Undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - "The Eggplant Epithalamion," 1971, 1976
      - Broadside/Card, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Poetry and Score, 1976 (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - "Erica Mann in a reading of her poetry," 1966 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - "Extras"--"For C.: concerning Blake" and "To the Muse," Undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Fruits & Vegetables, 1967-1975
      - General, Undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Contract, 1970-1974 (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence, 1971-1975 (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 20 to 21)
      - Drafts, 1967-1971
        - General, Undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
        - Notebook, 1967-1971 (Box 10, Folder 23)
        - Tissue Copy Manuscript, Undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
      - Reviews (Print), 1971 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Half-Lives, 1971-1973
      - General, 1971 (3 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 26 to 28)
      - Contract, Undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
      - Correspondence, 1972-1973, (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 30 to 31)
      - "From the Country of Regrets," Undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Manuscript Drafts, 1972, Undated (6 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 2 to 7)
      - Proofs, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Imagining Germany, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "Japanese Galleys", Undated (2 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 10 to 11)
    - Loveroot, 1974-1976
      - Contract, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Covers, Undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Drafts, 1975
        - General, Undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
        - "Author’s Corrected Pages," 1975 (Box 11, Folder 15)
        - "Author’s Set Galleys," 1975 (Box 11, Folder 16)
        - Manuscript, Undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
        - "Master Galleys," 1975 (Box 11, Folder 18)
        - "Master Pages," 1975 (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - Promotional Material, 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Love Comes First, Undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - "Old Poems," 1968-1971 (2 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 22 to 23)
    - "New Poems," 1979 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - "New Poems in Progress," 1987 (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Notebooks--#2: "Manuscripts of Half-Lives & Loveroot," 1973-1975 (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Notebooks--#4: "Beloit Poetry Journal, Heidelberg Poems & Manuscript of Fruits & Vegetables," 1961-1971 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Ordinary Miracles, 1974-1983
      - Drafts, 1983
        - General, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 6)
        - Galleys, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 7)
        - Proofs, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 8)
        - Typescript, 1983 (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 9 to 10)
      - "Extras," Undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - New American Library Edition--Interview, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Publicity Interview, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - "Poems on Jewish Experience," 1978 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - "Poetry Organizations," 1971-1983
      - "Authors Guild," 1977-1980 (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - "Poetry Award Bess Hokin," 1971 (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - "Women’s Forum," 1977-1983 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Songs in the Key of I, Undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Strand, Mark, Undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - This Garden, Undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Subseries II. 2: Fiction, 1973-2011